Guide to the Sheri Martinelli Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Sheri Martinelli papers
1905-1999
YCAL MSS 868
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
115.55
(131 boxes) + 13 art, 1 broadside, 1 roll
Correspondence, writings, artwork and objects, printed material, and sound recordings documenting the life and creative work of Sheri Martinelli and associated figures, including Ezra Pound. The correspondence includes Martinelli's letters with Pound, the poet H. D., and Charles Bukowski, as well as many other literary and artistic figures. The writings include selections of Pound's manuscript material from the Cantos, as well as Martinelli's extensive notes and notebooks. Paintings, sketches, ceramics, and etchings are present, as are two volumes of the Cantos, illustrated by Martinelli and housed in painted boxes, and extensive printed material containing Martinelli's illustrations and annotations. The sound recordings include over 1600 audiocassettes, microcassettes, and reel-to-reel tapes of recordings made by Martinelli's.
Martinelli, Sheri
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 3, 138-144 (reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 62-136 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 137 (microcassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Biographical/Historical note
Sheri Martinelli (1918-1996), artist and poet, was born in Philadelphia and studied ceramics at the Philadelphia School of Industrial Arts. Martinelli later expanded her artistic repertoire to include abstract painting and engraving. She became an associate of Anais Nin and William Gaddis in 1945 and met Ezra Pound in 1951 or 1952 while he was incarcerated at St. Elizabeth's Hospital in Washington, D. C. They maintained a relationship until 1956, and she provided him with inspiration for his work, including the Cantos, while he provided her with instruction in painting; he published a small booklet compilation of her work, La Martinelli, in 1956. She relocated to San Francisco in the late 1950s and began publishing the Anagogic & Paideumic Review, a literary periodical that published primarily Beat poetry, as well as poems by Charles Bukowski. Martinelli relocated to Virginia in 1984 and spent the rest of her life organizing the Pound-related papers in her possession.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: June 1977 Acquisition, August 1999 Acquisition, and August 1999 Acquisition Addition.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, artwork and objects, printed material, and sound recordings documenting the life and creative work of Sheri Martinelli and associated figures, including Ezra Pound. The correspondence includes Martinelli's letters with Pound, the poet H. D., and Charles Bukowski, as well as many other literary and artistic figures. The writings include selections of Pound's manuscript material from the Cantos, as well as Martinelli's extensive notes and notebooks. Paintings, sketches, ceramics, and etchings are present, as are two volumes of the Cantos, illustrated by Martinelli and housed in painted boxes, and extensive printed material containing Martinelli's illustrations and annotations. The sound recordings include over 1600 audiocassettes, microcassettes, and reel-to-reel tapes of recordings made by Martinelli.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Sheri Martinelli, 1977 and purchased from Gilbert Lee, 1999.
Artists -- United States -- Archives; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Illustration of books -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Modernism (Art); Modernism (Literature); Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiotapes -- United States -- 20th Century; Sound recordings -- United States -- 20th Century; Microcassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Etchings (prints) -- United States -- 20th Century; Sketchbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works) -- United States -- 20th Century; Sculpture (visual work) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Artists -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Martinelli, Sheri; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; H. D. (Hilda Doolittle), 1886-1961; Bukowski, Charles, 1920-1994
- June 1977 Acquisition, 1962-1969; 0.84; (3 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Sheri Martinelli, 1977.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, notes, printed material, and a reel-to-reel tape documenting the relationship of Sheri Martinelli and Ezra Pound.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in no particular order.
  - "Pound-Martinelli: Letters, notes and printed material", 1964-1979; 8 (Box 1)
  - "E.P. material", 1976
  - "Pound-Martinelli: Letters, notes and printed material", 1962-1976; 4 (Box 2)
  - "E.P. material", undated; 1; reel to reel tapes (Box 3)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Box 3 (Reel to reel tape): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- August 1999 Acquisition, 1905-1993; 114.5; (127 boxes)+ 13 art, 1 broadside, 1 roll
  Organized into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1938-1999. II. Writings and Research Files, 1937-1993. III. Artwork, 1925-1963. IV. Objects, 1957-1967. V. Books Annotated and Illustrated by Sheri Martinelli, 1905-1976. VI. Audiocassettes and Microcassettes, 1979-1993. VII. Reel-to-Reel Recordings, 1954-1976.
  Purchased from Gilbert Lee on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 1999.
  Correspondence, including Martinelli's letters with Pound, the poet H. D., and Charles Bukowski, and many others; Pound's manuscript material for the Cantos and Martinelli's notes; Martinelli's artwork; and over 1600 audiocassettes, microcassettes, and reel-to-reel tapes of Martinelli's recordings.
  - Correspondence, 1938-1999; Series I; 13.42; (14 boxes)
    - Unsorted, 1958-1982; 17 (Box 4)
    - Unsorted, 1952-1988; 15 (Box 5)
    - Unsorted, 1938-1987; 17 (Box 6)
    - Pound, Ezra; Lady, Lee; Gordon, Steve, 1940-1985; 7 (Box 7)
    - Unsorted, 1938-1999; 14
    - Unsorted, 1958-1990; 25 (Box 8)
    - Lee, Gilbert, 1956; 2
    - Lee, Gilbert, 1956; 2 (Box 9)
    - Horton, David T., 1969-1970
    - Notes, undated; 2
    - "Essex period", 1990-1991
    - Unsorted, 1952-1985; 14
    - Lee family, 1959-1961; 2
    - Lee family, 1956-1961; 2 (Box 10)
    - Sheri Martinelli family, 1951-1974; 13
    - Sheri Martinelli family, 1968-1973; 6 (Box 11)
    - Sheri Martinelli, 1958-1986; 7
    - Unsorted, 1961-1965; 8
    - Unsorted, 1964-1981; 5 (Box 12)
    - Horton, T. David, 1965-1985; 4
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1958-1960
    - Pound, Ezra
      - Letters to Martinelli, 1952-1960, 1981; 17
      - Letters to Lee Lady, 1958
      - Fragments, undated; 2
      - Postcards to Ezra Pound at St. Elizabeth's Hospital, Washington D. C., 1948-1958; 3
    - H. D. (Hilda Doolittle)
      - Postcards to Ezra Pound, 1958-1961
      - Letters to Sheri Martinelli, 1958-1961
    - Lady, Lee, 1969, undated
    - Major, Clarence, 1960-1962
    - Scott, Tom, 1971
    - Vinkenoog, Simon Treet, David Gaucher, D[ennis] Mullins, Eustace McDowell, Unidentified, 1950-1957, undated
    - Yankowski, [Stanley V.], 1963 (Box 13)
    - Joyce clippings and photocopies, 1967, undated
    - Bukowski, Charles
      - Correspondence, 1960-1967; 5
      - Photographs and notes, 1963, undated
      - Envelopes, 1960-1967; 3
      - Clippings, 1960-1964
    - Unsorted, 1952-1974, undated; 12
    - Unsorted, 1946-1984; 9 (Box 14)
    - Photograph, negatives and transparency, undated
    - Printed material, 1958, undated
    - Amaral, Jos, 1958-1960
    - American Mercury, 1957-1959
    - Applebaum, Beverly, 1950-1961
    - Balmont, Leo, 1951-1952
    - Bentley, W., 1960-1963
    - Berman, Wallace and Shirley, 1959
    - Castaldo, Joseph, 1952-1957; 2
    - Chatel, John C., 1957-1961
    - Clarke, Adele, 1960-1962
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1958-1961
    - Comfort, Howard, 1958-1959
    - Cookson, William, 1958-1962
    - Cronin, J. E., 1960
    - Donnelly, Leo Charles, 1957-1958
    - Emery, Clarke, 1959-1960
    - Fawcett Women's Group, 1955
    - Feick, Mattie, 1958-1961
    - Fostvedt, Jo, 1961-1962
    - Gade, Crystal, 1961 (Box 15)
    - Galler, David, 1960
    - Gould, Stanley, 1948-1958
    - Gray, Woods, 1956
    - Gumbiner, R. G., 1959-1960
    - Hesse, Eva, 1961-1962
    - Kono, Ichiro, 1958
    - Lady, Lee, 1958-1959
    - Lamantia, Philip, 1959
    - Lewis, Samuel L., 1960-1962
    - Louise, Mira, 1957-1958
    - Lyden, Nora, 1958-1960
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1957-1958
    - McIntyre, Alice T., 1957
    - McNaughton, William F., 1955-1960
    - Make it New Book Shop, 1952-1955
    - Martinelli, Sheri, 1957-1960; 3
    - Mayo, R. D., 1957
    - Miller, Vincent, 1957-1958
    - Mills, Kymrio, 1958-1963
    - Moore, Nancy, 1952-1962
    - Mossman, Bill Heine, 1952-1953
    - Murakami, Masayoshi, 1952-1955
    - Murray family, 1958-1959
    - Nazareth College, 1961
    - Odlin, R. W., 1957-1958
    - Owens family, 1952-1957
    - The Outsider, 1960-1961
    - Payne, Miles, 1959-1960
    - Puck, P., 1959-1960
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1958-1962; 3
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1957-1958
    - Schaefer, Rockwell B., 1960-1962
    - Shenandoah, 1957-1958
    - Sherman, Jory, 1960
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1959
    - Stresino, E., 1952-1955
    - Sisbey, Henry, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
    - Tze-Chang, Chao, 1955-1958
    - Vanni FRMP, 1958-1962
    - Vaughn, Robert, 1959-1960
    - Walker, Bernice, 1959-1962; 2
    - Wang, David Raphael, 1958, undated
    - Weiss, Phyllis, 1961
    - Yankowski, Stanley V., 1962
    - Zukofsky, Louis, 1958
    - Unidentified with notes and photographs, 1957-1961; 2
    - A-B general, 1960-1963; 2
    - C-D general, 1952-1962; 3
    - F-G general, 1952-1961
    - H-K general, 1950-1962; 2
    - L-M general, 1949-1962; 2
    - O-P general, 1951-1962; 2 (Box 17)
    - R general, 1954-1962
    - S-T general, 1948-1962; 2
    - U-Z general, 1951-1962
  - Writings and Research Files, 1937-1993; Series II; 8.21; (9 boxes)
    - Pound, Ezra
      - Autograph manuscripts
        - Cantos 90-95, 1954; 7 (Box 18)
        - "E. P.'s Prayer," "Honi Soit...," "Voice of Experience," "Prayer for a Dead Brother," "A Nice Quiet Heaven," ["Utopia,"] "Obscenity, etc...", 1954, undated
        - "Analects of Confucius, E. P. transl. S. M. commentaries", undated
    - Sheri Martinelli, n.d.
      - Cantos notes and photocopies, 1987, undated; 2
      - Texts, undated; 10
      - Texts (photocopies), undated; 2
      - Notes, 1963-1982, undated; 10
      - Notes (photocopies), undated; 2
      - Notes, undated; 9 (Box 19)
      - Notebooks, 1975-1983; 5
      - "Photocopies of Decorated Cavalcante," with annotations
        Photocopies of Sheri Martinelli's working illustrations for The Sonnets and Ballate of Guido Cavalcanti with translation and introduction by Ezra Pound.
        - Bound, undated
        - Title page, undated; 2
        - Introduction, undated
        - Sonetto II-VI, undated
        - Sonetto VIII, undated
        - Sonetto IX, undated
        - Sonetto XI, undated
        - Sonetto XII, undated
        - Sonetto XIII, undated
        - Pages 63, 92-93, 104-105, undated; 3
        - Notes and drafts, undated; 4
      - An Immorality, music score for voice and piano, words by Ezra Pound, music by Lee Hoiby, and cover illustration by Sheri Martinelli. Includes 1 photocopy, undated
      - Inventory, non-EP letters (photocopies), undated
      - Inventory, non-EP letters, booklists (photocopies), undated
      - "Anais Nin/Sheri Martinelli" (photocopies), undated
      - "Oriya/Edtn" (photocopies), undated
      - Duits, Charles (photocopies), undated
      - Miscellaneous (photocopies), undated; 2
      - "HD files" printed material and photocopies, undated; 16
      - Bilingual homage: Marianne Moore, English edition: printed material, notes and photocopies relating to the Zodiac, 1969-1993; 12
      - "To Mother on Mother's Day" poem by Hon. Henry R. Kissling, 1937 (Box 20)
      - Holy Land map, dust jacket and printed material, 1992, undated
      - United States map, undated
      - France map, 1989
      - Event calendar, 1965
      - "In Loving Memory of Turk" photocopies, undated
      - Photograph and photocopies, undated
      - "Cantos stuff" notes and photocopies, undated
      - Giovinezza, Inno dei Fascisti words and music by G. Blanc and Marcello Manni, undated
      - Mussolini clippings, 1993
      - Hemingway, Ernest, Washington Post Magazine clipping, 1957
      - Exhibit photograph and clippings, 1980
      - Exhibition invitation, Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts, 1956 August 23
      - Printed material, 1938-1982; 3
      - Clippings and printed material, 1964-1980, undated; 6
      - Notes and writings, 1940's, undated; 15
      - Notes and writings, 1958-1992, undated; 11 (Box 21)
      - Writings, 1962-1965, undated; 2
      - "American/Arts/Letters: Art/Artist Against Defamations Against Art/Artist," newsletter, 1980-1982; 3
      - Notes and writings, 1981-1992, undated; 7 (Box 22)
      - Notes and letters, 1964-1983, undated; 4
      - Notes and letters from Pearson and Clarence Major, 1959-1969, undated
      - Journals, 1954-1955; 3
      - Journals, 1956-1969; 13 (Box 23)
      - Journals, 1970-1980, undated; 10 (Box 24)
      - Journals, 1981-1983; 2 (Box 25)
      - Clippings, 1976
      - "Anagogic and Paideumic Review"
        Includes original drawings on mimeograph paper.
        - Volume 1:1-Volume 1:2, 1959
        - Volume 1:3, 1959; 2
        - Volume 1:4, 1960
        - Volume 1:5, 1960; 4
        - Volume 1:6 (H. D. Issue), undated; 2
        - Anagogic and Paideumic Portfolio of Art, production files, undated; 4
        - Anagogic and Paideumic Portfolio of Art, production files, undated; 3 (Box 26)
  - Artwork, 1925-1963; Series III; 2.83; (12 boxes), + 6 art, 1 broadside
    Primarily consists of sketches, drawings, paintings, etchings and etching plates made by Sheri Martinelli. Also includes some artwork of others.
    - Signed ink etchings and plate, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - 2 identical ink etchings and plate, undated; 3
    - "The Bird," etching and plate, undated; 2
    - "Boy and Cat," etchings and plate, undated; 2
    - "Charles Duit," etching, undated
    - "Negra," etchings and plate, undated; 2
    - "[Man] and Girl," etchings and plate, undated; 3
    - "Shelly," Initialled etchings, undated; 2
    - [Christmas] etching and plate, undated; 2
    - Untitled etching plate #1, undated; 2
    - Untitled etching and plate #2, 1946, undated; 2
    - Woodblock, drawing by Martinelli, cut by Poli, undated
    - "The Third African God, Dani balla," painting on wood, 1954 March
      Inscribed on back
    - Nudes, drawings, undated (Box 28)
    - "Portraits", undated
    - Ink and pencil drawings, undated; 2
    - Spiral notebooks with ink sketches and notes, undated; 2
    - "Brancusi," photographs and printed material, 1950-1955
    - 7 transparencies of artwork, undated
    - Art by Paul Kock, Iris Brody, Bill Heine, David Burnett, 1950-1959; 2
    - "Dixon, Mike, and Billie-Lew," drawing and printed material, undated (Box 29 (Oversize))
    - Ink and pencil drawings, etchings, and watercolors, undated; 7
    - Painting on canvas board, "[Andath]-Graham", undated
    - Watercolor profiles of Ezra Pound, undated (Box 30 (Oversize))
    - Watercolors and pencil sketches, undated
    - Nudes, faces, and abstracts. Ink, crayon, and pencil, undated
    - Pencil and ink drawings, undated; 2
    - "Salachi" poem and photograph collage on plywood, initialed, undated
    - Art work on mixed media, undated
    - Untitled, painting on canvas, undated (Box 31 (Oversize))
    - "My Iris Brody," painting on canvas, undated
    - Etchings, undated; 3
    - Faces and nudes, ink and pencil, undated
    - Pencil and watercolor drawings, undated
    - Photographs, most taken by Martinelli and initialed., undated
    - Tempo and Schweizer Illustreierte, 1957
    - San Francisco Examiner [2 issues, both front sections only]. Magazine clippings, 1961-1963
    - Illustrated copies of the Cantos
      The illustrated copies of the Cantos are housed in two handmade wooden boxes with some additional illustrations created and painted by Sheri Martinelli.
      - A Draft of XVI Cantos of Ezra Pound. Paris: Three Mountains Press. #64 of 70, 1925, undated (Box 32 (Oversize))
      - A Draft of the Cantos 17-27 of Ezra Pound. London: John Rodker. #64 of 70, 1928, undated (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - "Drawings, etc...many of Ezra Pound", undated (Box 34 (Broadside))
    - Abstract painting in green, brown, black and beige. Signed on the back of the canvas, "SM 23 Jones St. NYC.", undated (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - Abstract painting in greens, black, and yellow. "30" and "20" written on frame., undated (Box 36 (Art))
    - Abstract painting in greens, pinks and blues on wood. Signed on back, "Martinelli c/o Bob Lowden.", undated (Box 37 (Art))
    - Abstract painting of a human torso in greens and oranges. Signed on back, "Martinelli c/o Bob Lowden, SM.", undated (Box 38 (Art))
    - Abstract painting of a woman's head on paper on wood. Signed on the back, "Early NYC painting SM.", undated (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - "The Bridge." Painting initialed "SM" on the back of the canvas., undated (Box 40 (Art))
    - "How the Artist Keeps Herself A-Muse-D.", 1959 (Box 41 (Art))
      9 panel drawings etched and or painted on wood, varnished. Signed by Sheri Martinelli with her monogram in the lower right corner and dated 1959.
    - Portrait of a horned man in pink and green. Signed on the back of the canvas and the frame, "Martinelli c/o Bob Lowden.", undated (Box 42 (Overize))
    - Man seated in red, blue, and green on a gray background. Painting on wood. Framed. By unidentified artist., undated (Box 43 (Art))
    - "Two figures," oil on canvas, undated (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - "Female nude," oil on wood panel, undated (Box 45)
    - "Frosty Grampa" wood panel, undated
    - "Woman's face," watercolor, undated
    - "Zen free art. Outdoor exhibit..." Large poster of mermaid in gold and green with black lettering., undated (Box 145 (Roll))
  - Objects, 1957-1967; Series IV; 3.21; (4 boxes) + 7 Art
    Primarily consists of clay and ceramic sculptures and tiles, and objects belonging to or made by Sheri Martinelli. Photographic surrogates of the objects in this series are available in box 57.
    - "Venus," clay figure in the round, in three pieces, 1961 (Box 46 (Art))
    - Male face, [Ezra Pound?], clay sculpture, undated (Box 47 (Art))
    - Dragon, ceramic, undated (Box 48 (Art))
      Includes broken pieces
    - Lizard, ceramic, undated (Box 49 (Art))
    - Mermaid, ceramic, undated (Box 50 (Art))
    - Tiles, 1957-1967; 17 (Box 51 (Art))
      Consists of: "Children dancing," 4 tiles made by Po Li for Sheri Martinelli, one broken; woman and child on 1 plaster and 1 clay tile; "Isis" 2 green tiles; and 5 small ceramic tray/tiles, one broken
    - Untitled eye design on 6" x 4.25" glass pane (Box 52 (Art))
    - "Shell from Gary Li," woman's face drawn on a twisted gourd, undated (Box 53)
    - 2 small ceramic sculptures, undated (Box 54)
    - 3 small pieces, 1961-1962; 3 (Box 55)
      Consists of "Tears for H.D. Athena Weeping," drawing on unidentified media; "Sheri's Mask for Hallow's Eve," painted eye mask; and Nude figure of woman drawn on wood.
    - Ink stone, given to Martinelli by Ezra Pound, undated (Box 56)
      "The ink stone Ezra gave me in St. Liz. so I cd draw 'grampa a dragon'-SM"
  - Books Annotated and Illustrated by Sheri Martinelli, 1905-1976; Series V; 3; (3 boxes)
    Books contain annotations, drawings, illustrations, botanical specimens and ephemera of or created by Sheri Martinelli.
    - American Friends by Celia Zukofsky. New York: C.Z. Publications, 1979 (Box 57)
    - Bid Me to Live by Hilda Doolittle. New York: Grove Press, 1960
    - The Diary of 1944-1947 by Anais Nin. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1971
    - Ezra Pound at Seventy A booklet with quotes from Auden, Hemingway, Eliot. New York: New Directions, undated
    - The Hudson Review vol. VIII no. 4, winter 1955, 1954-60
    - L'Atre Della Nuova Guinea by Carl Kjersmeire. Milano: All'Insegna Del Pesce D'Oro, 1954
    - La Martinelli, Introduction by Ezra Pound. Milan, 3 copies, 1956
    - Papillion: Quattuor epigrammata Poems by Ezra Pound accompanied by sketches by Sheri Martinelli, 1957
    - Piero Della Francesca by Kenneth Clark. London; Phaidon Press, 1951
    - Pisanello by G. F. Hill. London: Duckworth and Company, 1905
    - Four Studies by Norman Holmes Pearson, printed in Italy, undated
    - Books by Ezra Pound
      - ABC of Reading by Ezra Pound. New York: James Laughlin, undated
      - Antheil and the Treatise On Harmony by Ezra Pound. Paris: Three Mountains Press, 1924
      - The Cantos of Ezra Pound, A New Directions book, 1948-1959
      - The Cantos of Ezra Pound, A New Directions book, 1971 (Box 58)
      - Thrones 96-109 de los cantares by Ezra Pound, 1959
      - Canto 98 by Ezra Pound, 1958
      - The Classic Anthology Defined by Confucius by Ezra Pound. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1954; 2
      - Collected Early Poems by Ezra Pound. New York: New Directions Publishing, 1976
      - The Chinese Written Character by Ernest Fenollosa, translated by Ezra Pound, undated
      - Confucian Analects translated by Ezra Pound. New York: Square $ Series, 1951
      - Drafts and Fragments of Cantos CX-CXVII by Ezra Pound. New York; New Directions Publishing, 1968
      - Guide to Kulchur by Ezra Pound. New York: New Directions, undated
      - Impact: Essays on Ignorance and the Decline of American Civilization by Ezra Pound. Chicago: Henry Regnery, 1960
      - The Letters of Ezra Pound 1907- 1941 edited by D. D. Page. London: Faber and Faber, undated (Box 59)
      - Literary Essays of Ezra Pound. New York: James Laughlin for New Directions, 1954-1958
      - Moscardino by Enrico Pea, translated by Ezra Pound. Milan: All'Insegna Del Pesce D'Oro, 1956
      - Patria Mia by Ezra Pound. Chicago: Ralph Fletcher Seymour, 1950-1954
      - Pavannes and Divagations by Ezra Pound. New York; James Laughlin for New Directions, 1958-1959
      - Pound's Artists: Ezra Pound and the Visual Arts in London, Paris and Italy. London: Tate Gallery Press, 1985
      - Rimbaud by Ezra Pound. Milan: All'Insegna Del Pesce D'Oro, 1957
      - Section: Rock Drill 85-95 de los cantares by Ezra Pound. All'Insegna Del Pesce D'Oro, Milano., 1955
      - The Sonnets and Ballate by Guido Cavalcanti with translation and introduction by Ezra Pound. Boston: Small, Maynard and Company, 1912, undated
      - The Spirit of Romance by Ezra Pound. New York: James Laughlin, undated
      - The Translations of Ezra Pound, New York: James Laughlin for New Directions, [1953]
      - Women of Trachis: A Version by Ezra Pound New York: James Laughlin for New Directions, 1957
    - Some Recent Finger-Painting of the Artist Mr. Wu Tsai Yen, 1948
    - Letters, notes, printed ephemera, and clippings by or relating to Sheri Martinelli, undated
  - Audiocassettes and Microcassettes, 1979-1993; Series VI; 78; (78 boxes)
    Boxes 62-136 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Box 137 (microcassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information